English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library, circa 1000-1820: First-line index.
English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library circa 1000-1820,
Mistress, your lily hand and rosy hue MS Eng 702, 6
Mitchell, thou Caledonian bard MS Eng 629, 56
Mix with your grave designs a little pleasure (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 80v
Moan hither all ye syllables of woe (incomplete) MS Keats 2.17.2
Mock on, mock on, Voltaire, Rousseau MS Eng 1167, 4 and 74
Moist with one drop of blood my dry soul MS Eng 966.7, 54v
Moist with one drop of thy blood my dry soul MS Eng 966.3, 96; MS Eng 966.5, 16; MS Eng 966.4, 81
Moll's a girl of discerning MS Eng 926, 48v
Moll, once in pleasant company by chance MS Eng 586, 88
Molly Mizen, Toby's wife MS Thr 198, folder 75
Moments there are in life, alas how few MS Eng 327 (88), 2
Monarch of all, with lovely fear MS Eng 614, 119
Monarchs, thus propt, the shocks of fate defy (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 12v
Money he hugs like any miser (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 80
Money's the life, the spirit of the laws (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 64v
'Mongst which, you, honored matron, who have seen (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 65
Mont Maior a Cartell free (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 4
Mony a time I rade wi' my brown foal (incomplete) MS Eng 1444, 22v
Moon shines night as day MS Am 2349, iii, p. 18
More active wealth doth that fair breast contain (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 98v
More blest, nor like this kiss, hath been another MS Eng 686, 44
More bravely British general never fell (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 81v
More had I seenbut now the god of day (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 107
More might be said hereof to make a proof (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
More might be said hereof to such a proof (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
More pleased, my foot the margin roves MS Eng 569.68, 8v
More private conference must end this matter (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 61
More speedy than behooves, death seems to be MS Eng 623
More than kisses, letters mingle souls MS Eng 966.7, 56v
Mortal! that man may'st understand aright (incomplete) MS Keats 1.64, 2
Mortal, that thou maist understand aright MS Keats 3.2, 180; MS Keats 4.20.8, 8
Mosey was a little man, a clever mare did buy (incomplete) MS Eng 1444, 28
Most blessed Jesu MS Eng 766, 193
Most careful shepherd, when I stray MS Eng 614, 45v
Most cruel mores hath killed the horse MS Eng 686, 13v
Most esteem of jewels for their worth MS Eng 702, 9
Most gracious and omnipotent MS Eng 631, 98
Most gracious God, which by thy providence MS Eng 623
Most gracious, sovereign lord, may't please MS Eng 629, 63
Most holy Paul, mine answer was MS Am 929, 89v
Most men reflect more strictly upon (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 32v
Most precious leaves the mail delights to bring MS Am 1817.2 (20), 7
Most subjects now are grown so trite MS Eng 834, folder 31
Most valiant guard! defenders of this pile MS Eng 674, 17
Most welcome love, thou mortal foe to lies MS Eng 1285, 72v
Most wretched men Are cradled into poetry by wrong (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 91
Most writers now-a-days are grown so vain (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 37
Mother of errors Rome we well may call MS Eng 612, ii, 76v
Mother of Hermes! and still youthful Maia MS Keats 3.2, 132; MS Keats 3.3, p. 65; MS Keats 4.20.9, 3
Mother of might and all sad thoughts that love MS Eng 626, 18v
Mount up, Jack, ye hae won the day (incomplete) MS Am 2349, i, 88
Mountains on whose barren breast (incomplete) MS Typ 603, folder 3
Mourn too, ye rural hinds, that near him dwelt (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 64v
Mow the beard (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 98v
Much gentil blude that wafic day (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 54v
Much has been said of strumpets of yore MS Eng 633, 22; MS Eng 585, 114v
Much have I travelled in the realms of gold MS Keats 3.12, 48; MS Keats 3.5, p. 18; MS Keats 2.4, 1
Much study many vainly do bestow MS Eng 614, 98v
Muggs had long wished to be a father MS Keats 3.9, 9v
Mumbles a kind of mental orison He knows not wherefore (incomplete) MS Eng 265, 7v
Mumph, frae a Millan, I'll bid you adieu MS Eng 1491, 32
Muse ere we part, let witty Arnold know MS Eng 228, 8
Muse, let us change our style, and live in peace MS Eng 633, 13v; MS Eng 585, 75v
Muse of my native land, loftiest muse (incomplete) MS Keats 1.14, 1v
Muses, inspire me with a serious vein MS Eng 625, 207v
Music, how tuneless and how cold MS Eng 505
Music, painting, and poetry, often proclaimed MS Thr 198, folder 27
Music removeth cares, sadness ejects (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Musician and physician eke MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 23
Music's soft powers may calm the troubled breast MS Eng 612, ii, 12v
Musing of late in Windsor bower sat MS Eng 512, 29
Musing upon the restless business MS Eng 532, lb
Must I read them again, sir?so here do stand MS Eng 988, 5
Must I, then, only border upon bliss (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 13v
Must thou a faithful lover go MS Eng 512, 12v
Must you needs go? hard heart necessity MS Eng 626, 21v
My auld wife she bangs me MS Eng 1497, ii, 134v
My beehives are furnished with bees MS Thr 198, folder 40
My blessing light upon my wife (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxi, 57
My bonny Liza Baillie MS Eng 1497, i, 48v
My bonny muir hen, my bonny muir hen MS Eng 1486 (3), 13
My bonny wee lassie, why what's a' the matter MS Eng 1486 (3), 22v
My books though small my Rome doth laud, doth love, doth loudly sing MS Eng 699, 9
My boy, a lively creature MS Eng 1461, 64
My bretheren all attend me MS Eng 1503 (1), 95v
My calling is domine, my parsonage fat and fair MS Eng 686, 87v
My charge was this, to translate by and by (incomplete) MS Keats 3.2, 75v
My charming Arabell, to make thee more secure, what would I not endure MS Eng 1038.1, 37
My cheek is pale For one whose cheek is pale: thou dost bewail (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 22
My Chloe, why do ye slight me MS Eng 512, 52v
My choir is fixed, let good or ill betide MS Thr 39, 29v
My coat shall be the linsey brown MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 88v
My comfort now I hope to find good fare (incomplete) MS Eng 623
My Conorhis cheeks are as ruddy as the morn MS Am 2349, iii, p. 25
My conscience is of stately mold, fit for the highest station MS Eng 1038.1, 2v
My country o'er the mountains wild MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 91
My days, and weeks, and months, and years (incomplete) MS Eng 614, 1
My days have been so wondrous free MS Eng 512, 42v
My dear and only love, I pray MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 177v; MS Eng 1497, i, 8
My dear Belladine Autograph file, G: John Gay, 1
My dear Mr. Moran MS Eng 935, urn, 4
My dear, though I from you am gone MS Eng 640, 21
My dear Tom Ingoldsby, right merry fellow Hew 1.3.1, 1st series, p. v.v
My dearest friend, I hope my heart MS Thr 198, folder 90
My dearest George! O could I once more view MS Eng 611, ii, 28v
My dearest Lord, farewell, let not a sigh (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 14v
My dere mayster (God his soul' quite) (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 3v
My Dolly was the snowdrop fair MS Eng 629, 81v
My Doris how could you suspect MS Eng 512, 22
My dreams did young and beautiful present (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xix, p. 9
My dull sickly husband, whom late I did wed (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 49
My eldest first, through misery MS Eng 1503 (3), i, 5 tipped in
My eyeballs start, my brain and heart's on fire (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 50v
My eyes furnish light'nings; my wings cloud the air (incomplete) MS Eng 1260 Folder 47, folder 47
My fair, ye swains, is gone astray MS Eng 895, 18
My father built a bonny bower (incomplete) MS Eng 862, 242
My father and Humphrey Hum were like brothers (incomplete) MS Thr 198, folder 12
My father fine would have me take MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 267v
My father he fee'd me far, far frae home MS Eng 1491 (3), 43v
My father he left me three plows and a mill MS Eng 1471, vii, 167v
My father he locks the doors at nicht MS Eng 1471, i, 144v
My father was a noble knight MS Eng 1470, 46
My father was the Duke of York MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 94v; MS Am 2349, xxiv, 396; MS Eng 1470, 36; MS Eng 1470, 208; MS Eng 1498, 31v
My father's the Duke of Argyll (incomplete) MS Eng 1471, vii, 49
My father's twine of life so slightly hangs (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 53v
My first and my last are as like as two peas MS Eng 569.67, 80
My first and second are the lot MS Eng 692, 20
My first and second are the same MS Eng 1323, 68v
My first denotes company MS Eng 569.67, 76
My first doth solace many an ancient dame MS Eng 569.67, 7
My first for pious use renowned MS Eng 692, 53
My first glad fears and joyful tremblings past MS Eng 228, 6v
My first in stately triumph bore MS Am 1177, 11v
My first is an emblem of purity MS Eng 692, 49v
My first is followed by my second MS Eng 692.1, 20
My first is my second, my second my first MS Eng 1502 (3),, 39v
My first is myself in a very short word MS Eng 1323, 31
My first is the hue of the unhealthy state MS Eng 1323, 23v and 35v
My first is the same in Latin as in French MS Eng 1323, 47
My first oft holds the miser's store MS Am 1177, 5
My first on yonder vet'ran tar behold MS Am 1177, 5v
My first than the night is more dark MS Am 1177, 4v
My first unceasingly pervaded MS Eng 569.67, 7
My first you may see at the end of your nose MS Eng 569.67, 5
My first you'll see men often taken MS Eng 692, 31
My first's a nasty, dirty beast MS Eng 1323, 67v
My first's a queen far famed in story MS Eng 1323, 33
My first's a small portion or physical ball MS Am 1177, 5
My first's a word that's sometimes heard MS Am 1177, 4v
My foolish rhymes on wedding days MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), no. 22
My fortune and my will this custom break MS Eng 966.5, 83
My frame of nature is a ruffled sea MS Eng 611, i, 33
My friend and I from home did part MS Eng 768 (vol. 1), 47
My friend, I'll not pretend the least your praise MS Eng 584, 68
My friend, my Celsus! (that's most eloquent MS Eng 228, 29
My friend, said she, 'tis easy to discourse MS Eng 612, ii, 16v
My George, were not the tie MS Eng 645, 55v
My God, be Thou my guide Autograph file, W: Charles Wesley, 1
My God (if I may call Thee mine) MS Eng 614, 124
My God, my God, how often have I thought MS Eng 625, 204
My God, the spring of all my joy Autograph file, W: Isaac Watts, 15v
My goddess, Celia, heavenly fair MS Eng 895, 86
My grateful first the senses charm MS Am 1177, 5
My grieved Muse can no more silent be MS Eng 623
My guardian, bear me on thy downy wing (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 75
My hay is stacking MS Eng 742, item 78, 1v
My head and tail both equal are MS Eng 1323, 41
My head is made of iron (incomplete) MS Eng 1471, vii, 147
My heart aches, and a drowsy numbness pains MS Keats 3.2, 157; MS Keats 3.1, 82
My heart forbodes her dead MS Eng 1038.1, 11v
My heart has thanked thee, Bowles, for those soft strains MS Eng 947.8, Effusion 1
My heart is by love forsaken, I feel the tempest glowing MS Eng 1038.1, 7v
My heart is sad to leave my friends MS Eng 1497, ii, 109
My heart, my blood, my soul, my care MS Eng 540
My heart was so free it roved like a bee MS Eng 1038.1, 49
My heart's affected with a weighty sense MS Eng 676F, 7v
My heart's in the highlands, my heart is na' here MS Eng 1497, i, 3
My home-bred Muse, kind, glorious saint forgive MS Eng 584, 95
My Honome, for features and for face MS Eng 569.66, 103v
My husband builded me a bower MS Eng 1471, vii, 100
My husband built for me a bower MS Eng 1444, 20 and 43
My husband dead! Ye Gods! what is't you mean (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 10
My innocence still wears a robe so white (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 30v
My Johnny ne'er could take delight (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 45v
My L. great G. W. seldom up the stairs MS Eng 699, 28v
My lady desires to speak with you MS Eng 785, 20
My lady hath forsaken me that long hath been her man MS Eng 1503 (1), 52v
My lady liege, said he, What all your sex desires is sovereignty (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 41
My lady reads, with judgement and good taste MS Am 1817.2 (20), 14
My lady's gown there's gairs upon it MS Eng 1497, i, 15v
My Lalage, when I behold MS Eng 626, 59
My lefe chyld I kownsel the MS Eng 534
My life's dear author, may your virtuous soul (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 69
My little dears who learn to read, pray early learn to shun MS Keats 3.13, ii, 38
My little sweet darling, my comfort and joy MS Eng 1494, 7
My limbs oft bore me Bounding o'er you blue tide as I have skimm'd (incomplete) MS Eng 630, 9
My loaf in my lap MS Eng 935, urn, 62
My Lord Cloncurry Come here in a hurry MS Eng 935, urn, 53v
My lord, I do confess the gods are with us (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 96v
My Lord Mayor and his aldermen and common council too MS Eng 629, 49
My lord, my dearest lord I see MS Eng 614, 48
My lord, some years disturb'd hath been my ghost MS Eng 1497, ii, 86
My lord, these errors merit our excuse (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 56
My lost William, thou in whom *EC8. Sh445. 929n, 21
My love and I for kisses played MS Eng 686, 81 and 83
My love band me with a kiss MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 265v
My love came to me when I was in drink MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 184v
My love for you shall never know my first MS Keats 3.13, i, 53v
My love he built me a bonny bow'r MS Eng 1470, 256
My love increaseth, and more and more will it increase MS Eng 540
My love, no other bound, than you does know (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 22v
My love she lives in Lincolnshire MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 123
My love she's like a pelican MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 31 tipped in
My love was born in Aberdeen MS Eng 1038.1, 59
My lovely charmer, will you dance MS Eng 512, 93
My love's hair's o' the bonny, bonny brown MS Eng 1471, v, 46v
My love's like the red, red rose (incomplete) Autograph file, B: Robert Burns, no. 4
My lucky and I gaed to the well MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 104v
My luve she lives in Lincolnshire MS Eng 1444, 18v and 39v
My maidens fair, your sets prepare (incomplete) MS Eng 1444, 21v
My masters, amd friends, and good people draw near MS Eng 636F, 83
My mind is vext and sair perplext MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 183v
My mind to me a kingdom is (incomplete) MS Eng 1503 (3), i, 115; MS Eng 1015, 14v
My mistress is more lovely and more fair (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 95
My mistress loves no woodcock MS Eng 686, 33v
My mither mend't my auld breiks MS Eng 1471, iii, 82
My mother groaned, my father wept MS Eng 1167, 57
My mother is a man MS Am 1177, 13
My mother mend'd my auld breeks MS Eng 1471, v, 141
My mother was a proud, proud woman MS Eng 1444, 10v
My mother was a proud woman (incomplete) MS Eng 1444, 40v
My mouth doth water, and my breast doth swell (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
My much loved Charlottine MS Eng 926, 30
My name ingraved herein MS Eng 966.3, 67; MS Eng 966.1, 49v; MS Eng 966.5, 127v; MS Eng 966.4, 184
My name is Do and here I lie MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 21v
My name is Prior. On the Cambridge road MS Eng 692, 14v
My name is William Guiseman MS Eng 1471, v, 27
My name it is bold Captain Grant, I'm bound for to say MS Eng 1470, 91
My name it is Robin Aboon MS Eng 1471, v, 123v
My name, my country, what are they to thee MS Keats 3.13, ii, 21
My name's Jocky Miller, I care not who knows it MS Eng 1497, ii, 60
My neighbor though to satisfy desire MS Eng 645, 12v
My next disguise too well you know (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 78v
My noble Hall MS Eng 645, 2v
My noble Deane, there be beneath my praise MS Eng 228, 17
My nose it bleeded three times last night (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xviii, p. 19
My palace stands on yon burn-brae (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 232
My panting heart beats to Erminia's breast (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 7v
My part is done, and you'll, I hope, excuse MS Eng 636F, 112
My Pegge is a young thing, just entered in her 'teens MS Eng 512, 83v
My Peggy is a saucy hen MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 109
My pen cannot express what my mind doth conceive MS Eng 1015, 88
"My pills," cries Bolus, "all disorders end" MS Eng 692, 24
My poor right hand! how I thy loss bewail MS Eng 676F, 29
My pretty children, hail MS Eng 1461, 63
My prime of youth is but a frost of cares MS Eng 686, 29; MS Eng 749, 161
My rantin', roarin' Willie MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 208v
My ranting, roaring Pluto MS Thr 198, folder 40
My reverend friend, I heard you say MS Am 505, 90v
My rod and my line, my float and my lead (incomplete) MS Eng 1490, 1v
My Sally's beautiful and bright MS Eng 895, 29v
My sermon o'er, I doffed my gown MS Eng 743, 1
My sins, good Lord, I have in mind MS Eng 757, 84
My sledge and hammer both declined MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 21
My soul does still enjoy its liberty (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 54v
My soul is darkoh! quickly strung MS Am 988, 24
My soul is with too great a load oppressed (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 25v
My soul, rejoice thou in thy God MS Am 1007, 38v; MS Am 1007.1, 27
My soul, thy grateful homage pay MS Eng 614, 54v
My soul's full of glory, which fires my glad tongue MS Eng 1143
My spectre around me night and day (incomplete) MS Eng 1167, 2 and 63
My spirit is too weak! Mortality MS Keats 3.2, 21; MS Keats 4.20.10, 3; MS Keats 4.7.20, 2v
My stock lies dead, and no increase MS Eng 614, 109v
My sun is gaen down and my heart it is sair MS Eng 1486 (3), 12
My sweetest sweet and fairest fair MS Eng 1500, 27
My thankful heart with glorying tongue MS Am 1007, 42v; MS Am 1007.1, 29v
My thirsty soul desires her draught (incomplete) MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 115; MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 184
My thousand lambs wander on yonder hills (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 101
My thoughts you cannot to revenge incline (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 27v
My time, O ye shepherds, was happily spent MS Eng 895, 51v
My times of sorrows and of joy MS Eng 614, 129
My title as a genius thus is proved MS Eng 1167, 77
My title as an [sic] genius thus is proved MS Eng 1167, 20; MS Eng 889, 13
My uncle Leigh is just come down MS Eng 742, item 81, 1v
My warlike first protects Brittania's coast MS Am 1177, 5
My wavering mind is tossed and toiled MS Eng 757, 90
My wife Joan has bid me tell MS Eng 742, item 81, 2
My wife she is the queen of all sluts MS Eng 1497, ii, 149; MS Eng 1471, vi, 23
My wounded soul with love, O Lord, and long desire of thee MS Eng 757, 110
Myn auctor, now Bochas writ, no lenger presse (incomplete) MS Eng 1482, Harl 2255, 93v
Myriads of torches fling (incomplete) MS Eng 265.1, folder 4
Myrtle leaf, that ill-besped MS Eng 947.2, 4v
N
N. long time was barren, bore at last a pair MS Eng 699, 25v
Nae heathen name shall I prefix Autograph file, B: Robert Burns, 1
Nail his neck to the cross nail it with a nail MS Eng 1167, 40; MS Eng 889, 33
Naked I came from out my mothers womb (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 82v
Naked she lay, clasped in my longing arms MS Eng 636F, 60v
Named humility and thankfulness MS Eng 247.5, 6
Nan and Frank, two quondam friends (incomplete) MS Eng 633, 26v; MS Eng 585, 136
Nansie's to the greenwood gone MS Eng 512, 41v
Narcissus loved and liked so his shape MS Typ 14, 35v
Nas byrnath Naefre hleothrede Tha hearo yeong cyning (incomplete) MS Eng 540
Nature and art in this together suit MS Eng 1167, 20; MS Eng 889, 13
Nature, and nature's laws lay hid in night MS Eng 569.65, 13
Nature amazed saw man without man's aid MS Eng 966.5, 13v; MS Eng 966.2, 3
Nature courts happiness, altho' it be MS Eng 606, 93
Nature depraved, abundance does produce (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 73v
Nature does strangely female gifts dispence MS Eng 633, 25; MS Eng 585, 127v
Nature, for defence, affords MS Eng 895, 33v
Nature has made man's breast no windows (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, ii, 17
Nature seeks corruption. Repentance finds grace MS Eng 1015, 75v
Nature, that washed her hands in milk MS Eng 626, 64
Nature, to show what she could do MS Eng 926, 21v
Nature walkest with me here If thou appear untouched by solemn thought (incomplete) *EC8. W8915.838s, p. 34
Nature withheld Cassandra in the skies MS Keats 3.2, 140
Nature's chief gifts unequally are carved MS Eng 569.63, 1
Nature's great masterpiece, the world's last sage MS Eng 623
Nature's lay idiot, I taught thee to love MS Eng 966.3, 21; MS Eng 966.1, 16v; MS Eng 966.7, 87; MS Eng 966.5, 64v; MS Eng 966.4, 150; MS Eng 686, 37
Nay, Bullstrodes self at the sound will quail MS Eng 935, urn, 48
Nay, Cupid, pitch thy trammel when thou please (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
Nay, in troth I talk but coarsely (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Nay, let me prove Onetha (incomplete) MS Am 35.5, 2v
Nay, old man, go not to the field MS Am 1972, 6v
Nay, painter, if thou darest design that fight MS Eng 624, 5
Nay, pish, nay phew, in faith, and will you? fly MS Eng 686, 35
Nay, prithee, be clear with us, and tell us (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 15
Nay, smile not to my sullen brow MS Am 988, 2
Nay, start not at that skeleton MS Eng 584, 14v
Nay, that which worldly art-worms call nonsense (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Nay, that which worldly bookworms call nonsense MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Near Bannockburn proud Edward lay (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 73
Near Port Collina, for devotion framed (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 2v
Near Reading there lived a buxom young dame MS Eng 1038.1, 69
Near the hill of Benachie MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 223v
Near the town of Linlithgow MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 144v
Near to Carlisle There dwells a knight MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 235
Near Woodstock town, in Oxfordshire MS Eng 895, 72v
Neatest of pretty feet, for dancing intended MS Eng 1038.1, 65v
Necessity doth urge the popinjay to prate MS Typ 14, 41v
Ned's father is a precise Puritan MS Eng 699, 26v
Needy knife-grinder, whither art thou going MS Eng 926, 57v; MS Keats 3.13, i, 9v
Ne'er let soft slumber seize your eyes MS Eng 680, 46v
Ne'er yet was a name so bandied by fame MS Eng 1038.1, 70v
Negrinus leads a married life MS Eng 629, 120
Nelson was once Britannia's god of war (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 74
Never by any painter but by thee (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 37v
Never, dear Faz, torment thy brain MS Eng 834, folder 33
Never let your heart despair MS Eng 512, 8
Never made man of a woman born (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
Never think you annoy MS Eng 1495, 4
Never was there tale of woe MS Thr 198, folder 48
New features speak the warmest heart (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 35v
New paths unfolding seek the north-sea tide (incomplete) MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), 52
News, ladies, glorious news, 'tis printed too MS Eng 629, 112v
News, news, news, news MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 4v
Never pain ["seek" deleted] to tell thy love MS Eng 1167, 58; MS Eng 889, 48
Never seek to tell thy love MS Eng 1167, 71
Next came a jolly troop of stagg'ring sots (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 67v
Next Chemia cameshe led (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
Next, close to him, crept Avarice the old (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 124v
Next close to Love, well-suited Marriage came (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 124
Next comes a little peevish elf (incomplete) MS Eng 1502 (3),, 121
Next, in a low-browed cave, a little hell (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 8
Next let the muse remember too (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 64v
Next morning, ere the sun with sickly ray (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 103
Next see, Lucretian sages, see the sun (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 72v
Next, wretched paupers, shed your briny flood (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 65v
Nice consciences, my lords, ye ken (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 39v
Night is a free and fetterless thing MS Am 567, 3
Night past, and all the shadows fled MS Eng 614, 70v
Nights dismal shade[s] once more are fled MS Eng 614, 83v
Nine days are passed and yet the wonder's now MS Eng 686, 55v
Nine days of dark prognostic had the sun (incomplete) MS Am 2349, v, p. 177
Nine days they marched; the tenth effulgent morn (incomplete) MS Am 1448 (nos. 20-63), 54
Nine tedious days a doubtful course we steer (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 40
Nine times a mother and not once a wife MS Eng 569.68, 1
No adverse fortune once shall him offend MS Eng 639, 19v
No breath of air to break the wave MS Eng 630, 63
No carpenter could by his trade Got so much coin as to have made gown of so rich stuff (incomplete) MS Eng 1107, folder 25
No cloud the azure vault of heaven distained MS Eng 934, 58